Contact

joshi.sujit@outlook.com +91 87881 48805

Currently in Bengaluru, originally from Pune.

Sujit Joshi

A service designer & researcher brimming with curiosity and a cando attitude, adept at systems thinking and carefully balancing user needs with business practicalities. Eagerly takes ownership, sparks collaboration, upholds the value of research, and goes out of the way to ensure project success.

Portfolio

https://sujitjoshi.com

Work Experience

Philips India Ltd. Service Designer II and

Service Designer I Sep 2021 to present Bengaluru, India

Service Designer II

- Scoped and led service design & research projects across various business verticals as part of an internal-facing consultative business transformation team in the healthcare technology
- Articulated the value of service design & research to C-suite members & program heads.
- Worked end-to-end- identified opportunities, designed interventions, tested, implemented, and evaluated new service experiences for healthcare professionals and patients.
- Conducted extensive qualitative research (on-field & virtual) with participants across the globe
- Designed end-to-end service experiences, customer journeys, UX prototypes, marketing assets, and non-digital touchpoints.
- Facilitated workshops among cross-functional teams to foster alignment, including internal workshops and 'clinics' to expand strategic & service thinking within the Bangalore design team
- Quantified CX impact via NPS, CSAT, modified versions of SUS scores to support iterative implementation of new experiences in key service moments of customer, user, and patient journeys.
- Started a Generative AI and Mixed Reality interest group of six members to find ways to improve overall customer experience, patient outcomes, & workflow efficiencies within Philips.

Studio 5B

Dr. Reddy's Laboratories Nov 2020 to Jul 2021 Mumbai, India

Service Designer

- Worked closely with UX designers, researchers, business stakeholders in cross functional teams during internship.
- Conducted research for new patient-facing services and identified opportunities to improve core internal processes
- Created end to end service blueprints to map as-is and future journeys, synthesized impactful insights from data gathered through primary and secondary research.
- Facilitated design thinking, needs-gathering, and brand strategy workshops.

Freelance positions

March 2020 to Jul 2021 Mumbai, India

UX Designer and Researcher

- Worked with a wide variety of clients including educational institutions, product companies, consultancies, startups, and nongovernmental organizations based in India and United States.
- Scoped and pitched projects, worked with other freelancers.
- Conducted market and user research, facilitated workshops, designed UX and UI prototypes of web-apps and internal dashboards with production specifications.

Research Methods Used

- Interviews
- Diary studies
- Shadowing
- Secondary research
- Method acting
- Heuristics evaluation
- · Service pilots
- A/B tests
- · Usability studies

Workshops facilitated

- Design Thinking (Train-the-trainer)
- Co-Create
- Brainstorming sessions
- Research alignment workshops

Artifacts created

- Service blueprints
- User experience and journey maps
- · Discussion guides
- Value network maps
- · Stakeholder maps
- Personas
- Empathy maps
- Process flow diagrams
- System diagrams
- Storyboards
- UX prototypes
- Wireframes
- Workshop materials
- 2D and stop motion animations
- Physical prototypes
- Web apps
- Interactive data visualizations

Languages

- English
- Marathi
- Hindi

MIT World

Peace University Jul 2020 to Oct 2020 Pune, India

Visiting Faculty- UX Prototyping

 Taught UX Prototyping to third year undergraduates through project-based learning. Expanded class to include discovery and evaluative research techniques based on students' requests.

Panorama Innovation

Jul 2019 to Mar 2020 Chicago, United States

Service Designer and User Researcher

- · Worked with clients in health insurance, city governance, and education fields in an innovation consulting role, bringing service design and research perspective to innovation programs.
- · Worked end to end, from conducting discovery research, designing new solutions, supporting pilots of interventions to evaluate impact.
- Facilitated design thinking training workshops, co-design workshops, and research-alignment workshops.
- Planned and conducted in-depth primary and secondary research (discovery and evaluative), created discussion guides, synthesized impactful insights.
- Created research tools such as online diary studies and card sorts.

Various organizations

Jul 2015 to March 2020

+ 5 more relevant experiences:

Data Visualization Designer and Developer, Researcher, Teaching Assistant, and Product Design & Engineering Intern

Education

School of the Art Institute of Chicago

Jul 2017 to May 2019 Chicago, United States

Master of Design, Designed Objects

Service Design and Research

Savitribai Phule Pune University

Jul 2012 to May 2016 Pune, India

Bachelor of Engineering

Mechanical Engineering

Recognition

iF Design Awards

iF Design Award 2023

April 2023

Service Design Category Associated with Philips India Ltd

School of the Art Institute of Chicago

Jan 2020 Chicago, United States

Polling Place

Alumni Exhibition in collaboration with Aimee Martinez Created new perspective to think about democracies and polling

MIT Media Lab

Jul 2017 to May 2019 Chicago, United States

Winning Team, Design.A.Hack.a.thon

MIT Media Lab & UC San Diego Design Lab